Guide to the Witold Gombrowicz Archive
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Audiovisual Materials, 1964-97; Series VII; 2.08; (5 boxes)
  - MOVING IMAGE MATERIALS
    - France 3 cinéma, Océaniques, Moi, Gombrowicz by Andrzej Wolski (part I) in French, [1989]; GENMSS515_0012; 1; 00:44:46; Sound on the tape is a little low. (Box 51, Item barcode 39002093673185)
      Running time: 45.38 min
    - Comédie-Française, Journal read by Andrzej Seweryn in French, 1997 Feb 15; GENMSS515_0001; 1; 00:44:18 (Box 50, Item barcode 39002093673078)
      Running time: 49.24 min
    - Le Films d'Ici and La Sept Cinéma, La moindre des choses by Nicolas Philibert, in French, 1996; GENMSS515_0002; 1; 01:39:57 (Box 50, Item barcode 39002093673086)
      Running time: 104.56 min
- Photographs, 1902-1997; Series VIII; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  Series VIII is organized into three subseries: Personal Photographs, Photographs of Theater and Film Productions, and Other Photographs.
  - PERSONAL PHOTOGRAPHS
    - "Gombrowicz en Pologne 1904-1939", photo album, 1902-39, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1385)
    - "Gombrowicz en Argentine 1939-1963", photo album, 1939-65? (Box 53, Folder 1386)
    - "Gombrowicz en Europe 1963-1969", photo album, 1963-69 (Box 53, Folder 1387)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS OF THEATER AND FILM PRODUCTIONS
    - Dziewictwo
      - Teatr Nowy w Poznaniu [Izabella Cywinska]: Dorota Lulka, Waldemar Szczepaniak, n.d. (Box 53, Folder 1388)
    - Ferdydurke
      - Ferdydurke, film (Poland, UK, France) [Jerzy Skolimowski], 1991 (Box 53, Folder 1389)
      - Teatr Nowy w Poznaniu, [Waldemar Smigasiewicz]: Waldemar Szczepaniak, Hadynski, Michal Grudzinski, 1991 (Box 53, Folder 1390)
    - Historia
      - Teatr Polski we Wroclawiu, 1995 (Box 53, Folder 1391)
    - Iwona
      - Teatro Experimental "Gil bicente" (Cascais, Portugal), [Carlos Avitz], 1971 (Box 53, Folder 1392)
      - Teatr im. Wilama Horzycy w Toruniu, [Krystyna Meissner], [1977] (Box 53, Folder 1393)
        Includes a letter
      - Teatr Polski we Wroclawiu, [Witold Zatorski], 1978 (Box 53, Folder 1394-1396)
      - Jersey City State College [Stefan Rudnicki], [1978?] (Box 53, Folder 1397)
      - Slezské divadlo v Opavé, 1991 (Box 53, Folder 1398)
      - Teatr im. Wojciecha Boguslawskiego w Kaliszu [Anna Augustynowicz], 1991 (Box 53, Folder 1399)
      - Teatr Ateneum [Waldemar Smigasiewicz, Maciej Wojtyszko], 1994 (Box 53, Folder 1400)
      - Teatr Polski w Szczecinie, [Marcel Kochanczyk], 1994 (Box 53, Folder 1401)
      - Unidentified theater company [Ingmar Bergman], 1995 (Box 54, Folder 1402)
      - Performance in Tokyo (Japan), 1997 Sep-Oct (Box 54, Folder 1403)
      - Zita Duarte (actress), n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1404)
      - Théâtre de l'Etuve, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1405)
      - Tarnowski Teatr im. Ludwika Solskiego, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1406)
      - Unidentified (Italy), n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1407)
    - Ja, Gombrowicz
      - Teatr Nowy w Lodzi [Wojciech Szulczynski], 1988 (Box 54, Folder 1408)
    - Kosmos
      - Teatr Powszechny im. Jana Kochanowskiego w Radomiu, 1995 (Box 54, Folder 1409-1410)
    - Operetka
      - Narodno Pozoriste Sarajevo, 1970
      - Suomen Kansallistteatteri, [1970-71] (Box 54, Folder 1411)
      - Teatro Technis-Karolos Koun, [1972] (Box 54, Folder 1412)
      - University of Rochester [Stefan Rudnicki], 1973 (Box 54, Folder 1413)
      - Teatr Nowy w Lodzi [Kazimierz Dejmek], 1975 (Box 54, Folder 1414-1415)
      - Teatr Slaski im. Stanislawa Wyspianskiego w Katowicach [Jerzy Zegalski], 1983 (Box 54, Folder 1416)
      - R.S.9 Studioszínház, 1993 (Box 54, Folder 1417)
      - Csokonai Színház (Debrecen, Hungary), 1995 (Box 54, Folder 1418)
        Includes newspaper clippings (photocopy)
      - Kharkivskii Derzhavvnii Akademichnii Ukrainskii Dramatichnii Teatr im. T. G. Shevchenka, [Gzhegozh Mruvchinskii], n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1419)
      - Théâtre National de Chaillot, n.d. (Box 54, Folder 1420)
    - Opetani
      - Teatr Polski we Wroclawiu [Tadeusz Minc], 1980 (Box 54, Folder 1421-1422)
    - Pornografia
      - Teatr Dramatyczny w Plocku [Grzegorz Sobocinski], 1989 (Box 55, Folder 1423)
    - Slub
      - Dramatiska Teatern (Stockholm, Sweden) [Alf Sjöberg], 1966 (Box 55, Folder 1424)
      - Schiller-Theater (Berlin, Germany), 1968 (Box 55, Folder 1425)
      - Teatr Dramatyczny Miasta Starego Warszawy [Jerzy Jarocki], 1973 (Box 55, Folder 1426)
      - Teatr im. Juliusza Slowackiego w Krakowie [Krystyna Skuszanka], 1975 (Box 55, Folder 1427)
      - Unidentified theater company in Tokyo, 1975 (Box 55, Folder 1428)
      - Teatr Polski we Wroclawiu, [Jerzy Grzegorzewski], 1976 (Box 55, Folder 1429-1430)
      - Theater Scena Polska Hamburg, 1985 (Box 55, Folder 1431)
      - Dramatiska teatern (Stockholm, Sweden), [Karl Dunér], 1995 (Box 55, Folder 1432)
      - Unidentified theater company, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1433-1434)
      - Unidentified theater company in Quebec, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1435)
    - Tancerz mecenasa Kraykowskiego
      - Compagnie du Réverbère (Paris, France), 1989 Mar (Box 55, Folder 1436)
      - Teatr Powszechny im. Jana Kochanowskiego w Radomiu, 1997 (Box 55, Folder 1437-1439)
    - Trans-Atlantyk
      - Teatr Polski we Wroclawiu, [Eugeniusz Korin], 1982 (Box 55, Folder 1440)
      - Unidentified theater company, (photocopies), n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1441)
      - Unidentified theater company, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1442)
    - Other
      - Teatr Ekspesji (Gdynia, Poland), 1990 (Box 55, Folder 1443)
      - Jerzy Jarocki, photograph by Wojciech Plewinski, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1444)
      - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1445)
  - OTHER PHOTOGRAPHS
    - "Witold Gombrowicz," Centre Georges Pompidou, Paris, exhibition 1991 Mar 26 - Jun 10, organized by Bibliothèque publique d'information (Box 55, Folder 1446)
    - Berlin, Akademie der Künste, exhibition 1992 May 10- Jun 28 (Box 55, Folder 1447)
    - Photographs of pictures by Acke Oldenburg, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1448)
    - Empty envelope annotated by a photographer, Thierry Boffelli, n.d. (Box 55, Folder 1449)
- Personal Papers, 1962-74, n.d.; Series IX; 1.23; (3 boxes)
  Series IX is organized into three subseries: Witold Gombrowicz Personal Papers; Gombrowicz Family Papers; and Writings of Family Members
  - WITOLD GOMBROWICZ PERSONAL PAPERS
    - "Swiadectwo dojrzalosci" [WG's school certificate] of 15 Jun 1922 (photocopy), n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1450)
    - "Tymczasowy dowód osobisty" [WG's temporary identity card] of 1922 Jun 23, (photocopy), n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1451)
    - KSK Spolem [protocols] of 1923 Jan 13 -Feb 3 (photocopy), n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1452)
    - WG's birth certificate of 1927 Sep 17 (photocopy), n.d.
    - University diploma of 1927 Oct 4, (photocopy), n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1453)
    - WG's passport of 1937 (photocopy), n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1454)
    - "Certificado procesal (moralidad)/ Swiadectwo moralnosci i dobrych obyczajow [certificate of morality and good conduct], 1939 Jul 26 (Box 56, Folder 1455)
    - WG's birth and baptism certificate of 1949 Apr 22 (photocopy) (Box 56, Folder 1456)
    - Banco Polaco in Buenos Aires, photograph (printed material), n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1457)
    - WG's Argentinian passport of 1964 Sept 9 (photocopy), n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1458)
    - "Federico C." [travel booklet and postcard], 1962 Jun (Box 56, Folder 1459)
    - "Kosztorys istnienia" [notes and figures related to financial matters], holograph, [ca. 1964] (Box 56, Folder 1460)
    - "Zdrowie" [notes on WG's health from 1964 May 17 to 1966 Jun] (Box 56, Folder 1461)
    - List of persons who sent letters of congratulation, telegrams or flowers on WG's receiving the Prix International des Editeurs, holograph, 1967 May (Box 56, Folder 1462)
    - Notes about editions of WG's works in different countries, holograph, 1967 Dec 1 (Box 56, Folder 1463)
    - List of names, holograph, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1464)
    - Notes and figures related to income in 1965-68, holograph (Box 56, Folder 1465)
    - Plan for arranging WG's correspondence for RG in Vence, holograph (Box 56, Folder 1466)
    - Family trees, holograph, 1968 (Box 56, Folder 1467)
    - Family trees, typescript and typescript carbon (Box 56, Folder 1468)
    - Plan for renovation of Villa Alexandrine (Box 56, Folder 1469)
    - Lists of names and addresses, holograph, typescript (Box 56, Folder 1470-71)
    - Manuscript notes (in Spanish, third party handwriting) taken out of the copy of Lecciones preliminares de filosofía by Manuel García Morente (Box 56, Folder 1472)
    - Original folder annotated by WG, n.d. (Box 56, Folder 1473)
  - GOMBROWICZ FAMILY PAPERS
    - Biblioteka Narodowa (Poland), microfilm, 1974 (Box 57, Folder 1474-1476)
      Contains reproductions of documents relating to the history of the Gombrowicz family, from Archiwum rodzinne Szymkowiczow-Gombrowiczow (Szymkowicz-Gombrowicz family archive) from 17th to 20th century
    - Osrodek Informacji Naukowej (Polska Akademia Nauk), microfilm, n.d. (Box 57, Folder 1477)
      Contains reproductions of the manuscript materials pertaining to WG, held by Polska Akademia Nauk (catalog number Rps Zb Wl. 90): personal and family papers (1892-1933), WG's works (ca. 1925), WG's correspondence with Jerzy Gombrowicz and Irena Gombrowicz (1957-65) diverse materials relating to WG (1918-39)
  - WRITINGS OF FAMILY MEMBERS
    - Gombrowicz, Antonia "Co wiem i pamietam o rodzinie" typescript corrected, n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1478)
    - Scibor-Kotkowski, Andrzej, "Wspólnota rodzinna Scibor-Kotkowskich w Bodzechowie," typescript corrected (photocopy) (Box 58, Folder 1479)
    - Gombrowicz, Jerzy, "Komentarz biograficzny do twórczosci Witolda Gombrowicza" [thesis commissioned by Polska Akademia Nauk], typescript carbon, bound, 1967 Jul (Box 58, Folder 1480)
    - Gombrowicz, Jerzy, "Mój brat Witold i nasi przodkowie," printed version (photocopy of article from 1972 Mar), n.d. (Box 58, Folder 1481)
    - Unidentified, genealogical notes and family trees, manuscript (Box 58, Folder 1482)
- Rita Gombrowicz Papers, 1969-97; Series X; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  Series X is organized into five subseries: Correspondence; Research Files; Writings of Rita Gombrowicz; Newspaper Clippings; and Printed Ephemera
  - CORRESPONDENCE
    - Letters of Condolence
      - Albert Bonniers Förlag, 1969 Aug 1 (Box 59, Folder 1483)
      - Athenaeum - Polak & Van Gennep, 1969 (Box 59, Folder 1484)
      - Beers, Paul, 1969 (Box 59, Folder 1485)
      - Belfond, Pierre, 1969 Aug 9 (Box 59, Folder 1486)
      - Brabant, Roger, 1969, Sep 6 (Box 59, Folder 1487)
      - Claudel, Jacques, 1969 (Box 59, Folder 1488)
      - Coxhead, David, 1969 Oct 25 (Box 59, Folder 1489)
      - Dubuffet, Jean, 1969 (Box 59, Folder 1490)
      - [Garthe, Hanne], 1969 Jul 30 (Box 59, Folder 1491)
      - Glaz, Kazimierz, 1969 Jul 30 (Box 59, Folder 1492)
      - Griffith-Jones, Krystyna, 1969 Aug 1 (Box 59, Folder 1493)
      - Grove Press, 1969 Jul 28 (Box 59, Folder 1494)
      - Guillemant, J----, [1969 Jul] 25 (Box 59, Folder 1495)
      - Hémery, Jean Claude, 1969 Jul 25 (Box 59, Folder 1496)
      - Janta, Aleksander, 1969 Jul 29 (Box 59, Folder 1497)
      - Jelenski, Constantin, 1969, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1498)
      - Koukou Chanska, 1969 Aug 2 (Box 59, Folder 1499)
      - [Kotkowski] Gustaw, 1969 Jul 25 (Box 59, Folder 1500)
      - Librairie J.P. Champagne, 1969 Aug 6-25 (Box 59, Folder 1501)
      - Lubomirska, Ada, 1969 Aug 21 (Box 59, Folder 1502)
      - Marié, François, 1969 Aug 6 (Box 59, Folder 1503)
      - Mrozek, Slawomir, 1969 Jul 25 (Box 59, Folder 1504)
      - Peterkiewicz, Jerzy, 1969 Aug 3 (Box 59, Folder 1505)
      - Orme, Alexandra, 1969 Oct 12 (Box 59, Folder 1506)
      - Radio Free Europe, 1969 Aug 5 (Box 59, Folder 1507)
        Contains a letter written by Jan Nowak on behalf of RFE
      - Richter, Rudolf, 1969 (Box 59, Folder 1508)
      - Robin, Pierre, 1969 Aug 12 (Box 59, Folder 1509)
      - Roux, Dominique de, 1969 Jul 28 (Box 59, Folder 1510)
      - Read, Piers Paul, 1969 Aug 31 (Box 59, Folder 1511)
      - Sanavio, Piero, 1969 Jul 26 (Box 59, Folder 1512)
      - Sandauer, Artur, 1969, Aug 6-15 (Box 59, Folder 1513)
      - Swieczewska, Maria, 1969 Jul 29 (Box 59, Folder 1514)
      - Tarnawski, Wit, 1969 Jul 25 (Box 59, Folder 1515)
      - Tiel, Walter
        See: Richter, Rudolf, box 59, folder 1508
      - Volle, Jacques, 1969 Aug 22 (Box 59, Folder 1516)
      - General and unidentified, 1969 (Box 59, Folder 1517)
      - Telegrams, 1969 (Box 59, Folder 1518)
        Includes telegrams from: Jerzy Andrzejewski; Biblioteka Polska w Paryzu; Christian Bourgois; Tadeusz Breza; Stanislawa Cichowska; Evelyne Creed; Hanne Garthe; Alastair Hamilton; Constantin Jelenski; Stanislaw Kasprzycki; Andrzej Kijowski; Koukou Chanska; Yukio Kudo; Kultura; Grytzko Mascioni; Czeslaw Milosz; Napoleon Murat; Günther Neske; Jan Nowak; Michel Polac; Jacques Rosner; Dominique de Roux; Geneviève Serreau; Theatro Stabile Aquila; Wiadomosci (Mieczyslaw Grydzewski)
      - Postcards and visiting cards, 1969 (Box 59, Folder 1519)
        Includes postcards and visting cards of: Suzanne Arlet; Kazimierz Brandys; Hanne Garthe; Waclaw Zyndram Koscialkowski; Czeslaw Milosz; Jacques Robnard; Pierre Vincent
      - Guest book of persons present at WG's funeral ceremony, 1969 Jul 26 (Box 59, Folder 1520)
    - General Correspondence
      - Arlecchino Teaterförlag Bertil Bodén, 1969-70 (Box 59, Folder 1521)
      - Arrighi, Niké, 1970 (Box 59, Folder 1522)
      - Autrement dit (association), 1992 Feb 17 (Box 59, Folder 1523)
      - B" general, 1970 Feb 27 (Box 59, Folder 1524)
      - Beers, Paul, 1994 Nov 28 (Box 59, Folder 1525)
      - Belfond (Firm), 1972 (Box 59, Folder 1526)
        Accompanied by the list of errors in the translation of Entretiens avec Gombrowicz
      - Bondy, Luc, 1970-71 (Box 59, Folder 1527)
      - Boscq, Jean Pierre, 1972 (Box 59, Folder 1528)
      - Edicions 62, 1974 Nov 18 (Box 59, Folder 1529)
      - Gale Research Inc., 1969, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1530)
        Includes a letter of 1969 Aug 21 and a leaflet
      - Jelenski, Constantin, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1531)
      - Koukou Chanska, 1970-73 (Box 59, Folder 1532)
        Includes third party correspondence, newspaper clipping
      - Nouveau Théâtre de Bourgogne, 1985 May 13 (Box 59, Folder 1533)
      - Richter, Rudolf, 1970-74 (Box 59, Folder 1534)
        Includes a letter from RR's wife
      - Roux, Dominique de, 1972 Feb 7 (Box 59, Folder 1535)
      - S.Fischer Verlag, 1988-91 (Box 59, Folder 1536)
        Newspaper clippings have been removed to Series XI. Clippings
      - Sábato, Ernesto R., 1978-88 (Box 59, Folder 1537)
      - Tiel, Walter
        See: Richter, Rudolf box 59, folder 1534
  - RESEARCH FILES
    - Persons and Institutions
      - Bachmann, Ingeborg, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1538)
      - Belfond (Firm) (Box 59, Folder 1539)
      - Brzozowska-Lukasiewicz, Aniela (Box 59, Folder 1540)
      - Deutsches Akademisches Austauschdienst, n.d. (Box 59, Folder 1541)
      - Feltrinelli, Giangiacomo, 1967-73 (Box 60, Folder 1542-1543)
        Includes brochure In memoria di Giangiacomo Feltrinelli and book catalogues of 1967
      - Ford Foundation (Box 60, Folder 1544)
      - Giangrande, Alicja, 1955-69 (Box 60, Folder 1545)
      - Giedroyc, Jerzy, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1546)
        Contains the list of the correspondence between WG and Jerzy Giedroyc preserved in the archive of Kultura
      - Grass, Günther, 1984 Oct 31 (Box 60, Folder 1547)
        Contains an interview conducted by RG for Gombrowicz en Europe
      - Grodzicka, Halina, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1548)
        Contains "Las tres coronas de Gombrowicz," typescript, (photocopy)
      - Hartung, Rudolf, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1549)
      - Jelenski, Constantin, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1550)
        Contains a fragment of CJ's letter [of 1963?] to Czeslaw Milosz (transcript, photocopy).
      - Johnson, Uwe, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1551)
      - Julliard (Firm), n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1552)
        Contains note by RG "Bourgois-Julliard situation"
      - Kosko, Allan, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1553)
        Includes an article about AK written by Janusz Odrowaz-Pieniazek
      - Lis-Kozlowski, Stanislaw, 1958-62 (Box 60, Folder 1554)
        Contains brochures: Washington y Kosciuszko by Wladyslaw M. Kozlowski and Skarby wawelskie by Stanislaw Lis-Kozlowski
      - Literarisches Colloquium Berlin, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1555)
      - Marion Boyars Publishers [catalogues], [1992-97] (Box 60, Folder 1556)
      - Mayewski, Pawel, 1997 Nov 19 (Box 60, Folder 1557)
      - Nadeau, Maurice, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1558)
        Includes: MN's articles on WG's works(photocopies) and "Historia de l'Edition Française" (note by RG)
      - Neske, Günther, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1559)
      - Paczowski, Bohdan, 1977 Jun (Box 60, Folder 1560)
        Contains an issue of Domus. Monthly magazine of Architecture, Dessigne, Art with design by BP
      - Roux, Dominique de, 1995 (Box 60, Folder 1561)
        Includes "Dominique de Roux: une culture intellectuelle du Tragique" by Joël Jégouzo
      - Sandauer, Artur (Box 60, Folder 1562)
      - Sédir, Georges, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1563)
      - Weiss, Peter, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1564)
    - Theater
      - "Carte théâtrale de Pologne" [map], print, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1565)
      - Csokonai Színház (Debrecen, Hungary), 1995-96 (Box 60, Folder 1566)
      - Kunliga Dramatiska Teatern (Stockholm, Sweden), 1993 Apr (Box 60, Folder 1567)
      - Lavelli, Jorge, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1568)
      - Narodno Pozoriste (Belgrade, Serbia), 1970-71 (Box 60, Folder 1569)
      - Oldenberg, Acke, 1969 (Box 60, Folder 1570)
      - Rudnicki, Stefan, 1963 (Box 60, Folder 1571)
      - Studio Teatr Test, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1572)
      - Teatr Ekspresji (Gdynia, Poland), 1990 (Box 60, Folder 1573)
        See also: Series VIII. Photographs, Teatr Ekspresji (Gdynia, Poland), box 55, folder 1443
      - Teatr im. Stanislawa Ignacego Witkiewicza w Zakopanem, 1985-93, n.d. (Box 60, Folder 1574-1575)
      - Teatr Nowy w Poznaniu, 1990-93 (Box 61, Folder 1576)
      - Teatr Stary w Krakowie, 1990-92 (Box 61, Folder 1577)
      - Teatr Stu w Krakowie, 1990? (Box 61, Folder 1578)
      - Théâtre National de la Colline, 1988-89 (Box 61, Folder 1579)
      - Wooster Group, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1580)
      - Other, 1994-95, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1581)
    - Other Files
      - Ferdydurke, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1582)
      - French translations of Polish articles, manuscript and typescript (Box 61, Folder 1583-1584)
        Includes notes about newspaper articles and envelopes in which the clippings were sent
      - Empty envelopes, 1976-97, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1584a)
        Contains envelopes in which theater programs and photographs of theater performances were sent
      - "Swinarska's case"
        - "Campagne de presse en Pologne contre Gombrowicz 25 août-22 decembre 1963, 2 versions, typescript annotated, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1585)
      - Newspaper clippings (photocopies), n.d.
      - Synopses of several of WG's works, in Polish, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1586)
      - Fragment of Gombrowicz i krytycy, [published 1974], printed material (photocopy), n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1587)
      - List of German magazines, typescript, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1588)
  - WRITINGS OF RITA GOMBROWICZ
    - Gombrowicz, Rita, "Disques de Witold Gombrowicz 1965-1969 à Vence," notes, manuscript, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1589)
    - "Witold Gombrowicz. Chronologie et oeuvres," computer printout, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1590)
      Includes an advertisement by Librairie Gallimard
    - Glowinski Michal, "Wokól ksiazek Rity Gombrowicz i Rajmunda Kalickiego," [review], typescript carbon (Box 61, Folder 1591)
    - Review of "Gombrowicz en Europe", n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1592)
    - Publicity material, 1984-94 (Box 61, Folder 1593)
  - NEWSPAPER CLIPPINGS
    - English clippings, 1984
    - French clippings, 1984-89
    - Italian clippings, 1991
    - Polish clippings, 1991
    - Polish clippings, 1991-97, n.d.
    - Swedish clippings, 1990
      Contains a whole issue of DN. Kultur & Nöjen
  - PRINTED EPHEMERA
    - Les belles étrangeres. Pologne, [brochure about contemporary Polish writers], 1990 Dec 8 (Box 61, Folder 1594)
    - Fondation Royaumont, Francis Maréchal 1984 (Box 61, Folder 1595)
    - Goüin, Henry, L'Abbaye de Royaumont, 1985 Nov (Box 61, Folder 1596)
    - Vence [Series: Connaissance des Arts ], 1994 (Box 61, Folder 1597)
    - Tourist information about Poland and Polish culture (brochures), 1997, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 1598)
- Clippings, 1933-1998; Series XI; 74.94; (48 boxes)
  Series XI consists of two subseries: Whole Issues Containing Articles Pertaining to Gombrowicz and Newspapers Clippings. Both subseries are arranged into language groups, listed in alphabetical order. The items within the language groups are arranged in the first subseries alphabetically, and in the second chronologically.
  - WHOLE ISSUES CONTAINING ARTICLES PERTAINING TO GOMBROWICZ
    - Croatian
      - Knjizevna smotra, Nr 3, 1970 (Box 62, Folder 1599)
    - Dutch
      - Vrij Nederland Boekenbijlage, Nr 37, 1986 Sep 13
    - English
      - New York Review of Books, Vol. XLI, Nr 16, 1994 Oct 6
      - Times Literary Supplement, Nr 4,479, 1989 Feb 3-9
      - Warszawa, Vol. 3, Nr 9, 1993 Sep (Box 62, Folder 1600)
        Magazine includes Polish and German versions of articles
      - Yale Spring 1994 (Box 62, Folder 1601)
    - Finnish
      - Ramppi, Nr 1, 1971 (Box 62, Folder 1602)
    - French
      - 10/18, [1982?] (Box 62, Folder 1603)
      - 10/18, [1985?]
      - 10/18, [1996?]
      - Acta Hispanica. Mélanges offerts à Paul Roche (Université de Nantes), 1992 (Box 62, Folder 1604)
        Inscribed by Lilianne Hasson
      - Acta Universitatis Wratislaviensis. Gombrowicz. Actes du Colloque de l'Université de Lille 3 (le 29 Mai 1980), 1985 (Box 62, Folder 1605)
      - Ane: le magazine freudien Nr 17, 1984 Jul-Aug
      - Ane: le magazine freudien, Nr 89, 1989 Jan-Mar
      - Art press, Nr 81, 1984 May (Box 62, Folder 1606)
      - Art press, Nr 140, 1989 (Box 62, Folder 1607)
      - Art Press, Nr 207, 1995 Nov (Box 62, Folder 1608)
      - Bakakaï, [1990] (Box 62, Folder 1609)
      - Bleu Nuit, Nr 9/10, 1985 (Box 62, Folder 1610)
      - Bref (Paris, France), Nr 125, 1969 Jun-Jul (Box 62, Folder 1611)
      - Bref (Paris, France), Nr 126, 1969 Oct (Box 62, Folder 1612)
      - Bref (Paris, France), Nr 128, 1969 Dec (Box 62, Folder 1613)
      - Bulletin Gallimard, Nr 412, 1996 Mar-Apr (Box 62, Folder 1614)
      - Bulletin Gallimard, Nr 417, 1997 Mar-Apr (Box 62, Folder 1615)
      - Cahiers du cinéma, Nr 439, 1991 Jan (Box 62, Folder 1616)
      - Cahiers du cinéma, Nr 441, 1991 Mar (Box 62, Folder 1617)
      - Découvertes Gallimard, 1995 Apr-Jun (Box 62, Folder 1618)
      - Découvertes Gallimard, 1996 Apr-Jun (Box 62, Folder 1619)
      - L'Evénement, Nr 575, 1995 Nov (Box 62, Folder 1620)
      - L'Express, Nr 1307, 1976 Jul-Aug (Box 62, Folder 1621)
      - L'Express, nr 2001, 1989 Nov 10-16 (Box 62, Folder 1622)
      - Express international, Nr 2008, 1990 Jan 5 (Box 63, Folder 1623)
      - Folio, 1995 Apr-Jun (Box 63, Folder 1624)
      - France-Pologne, Nr 234, 1991 (Box 63, Folder 1625)
      - Inrockuptibles Nr 19, 1989 Oct-Nov (Box 63, Folder 1626)
      - Inrockuptibles Nr 68, 1996 Aug-Sep (Box 63, Folder 1627)
      - Journal de Chaillot, Nr 17 (3 copies), 1984 May (Box 63, Folder 1628)
      - Kanal+- Magazine, Nr 3, 1984 Apr-May (Box 63, Folder 1629)
      - Lecteur, Nr 2, 1997 Mar
      - Libération, Nr 872, 1984 Mar 9
      - Lire, Nr 103, 1984 Apr (Box 63, Folder 1631)
      - Magazine littéraire, Nr 340, 1996 Fev (Box 63, Folder 1632)
      - Marianne, Nr 37, 1998 Jan 5-11 (Box 63, Folder 1633)